In the last video, we painted and transferred muscle origins and insertions.
지난 영상에서는 근육의 기시와 정지(부착점)를 페인트하고 전달(Transfer)했습니다.
We also computed muscle fiber field and other data that's related to muscle contraction.
또한 근수축과 관련된 근섬유 필드와 기타 데이터를 계산했습니다.
Let's define some constraints that will drive the tetrahedral mesh during the simulation.
이제 시뮬레이션 동안 테트라 메시에 영향을 줄 제약(Constraints)을 정의해 봅시다.
Our muscle simulation uses an inside-out approach, meaning that the animated bones will drive the muscles and also then the fat layer.
우리의 근육 시뮬레이션은 ‘inside‑out’ 접근을 사용합니다. 즉, 애니메이션된 뼈가 근육을 구동하고, 이어서 지방층도 구동합니다.
Let's bring in the bones.
이제 뼈를 가져오겠습니다.
Create a new skeletal mesh node.
새로운 Skeletal Mesh 노드를 만듭니다.
Let's set that to be the bones.
그 노드를 뼈(Skeleton)로 설정합시다.
Let's go ahead and convert that to a collection so that we can visualize it.
시각화할 수 있도록 이를 컬렉션으로 변환해 줍니다.
Now we can see there's the bones of the character.
이제 캐릭터의 뼈가 보입니다.
Let's select both nodes so that we can see both the muscles and the bones.
근육과 뼈를 모두 볼 수 있도록 두 노드를 모두 선택합시다.
We'll first create some kinematic constraints to constrain the muscle attachments to the bones.
먼저 근육 부착점을 뼈에 고정하는 키네마틱 제약을 만들겠습니다.
The definition of a kinematic constraint is that the position of the kinematic vertex will be linearly skinned during the simulation.
키네마틱 제약이란, 키네마틱 버텍스의 위치가 시뮬레이션 동안 선형 스키닝(linear skinning)된다는 의미입니다.
The motion of the simulation is mostly driven by kinematic constraints that move according to the joint transforms from each frame of the animation.
시뮬레이션의 움직임은 주로 각 프레임의 조인트 변환을 따르는 키네마틱 제약에 의해 구동됩니다.
Let's go ahead and create a new node called kinematic muscle attachments.
이제 ‘Kinematic Muscle Attachments’라는 새 노드를 만들겠습니다.
This node will kinematic bind muscle attachments, which is the muscle origins insertions that we just painted.
이 노드는 방금 페인트한 근육의 기시/정지를 키네마틱으로 바인딩합니다.
And then kinematic bind them to the skeletal mesh, which is the bone.
그리고 그것들을 뼈에 해당하는 Skeletal Mesh에 키네마틱으로 바인딩합니다.
So connect collections and also the origins insertion indices.
따라서 컬렉션과 기시/정지 인덱스를 연결해 주세요.
And also give the skeletal mesh of the bones here.
또 여기에는 뼈의 Skeletal Mesh도 지정합니다.
Now we can visualize the kinematic attachments through a visualize kinematic faces node.
이제 ‘Visualize Kinematic Faces’ 노드를 통해 키네마틱 부착을 시각화할 수 있습니다.
Now with that node selected, you can see these are the kinematic faces that's created from this node.
해당 노드를 선택하면, 이 노드에서 생성된 키네마틱 페이스들을 볼 수 있습니다.
I do want to point out that this does not see any internal vertices and can only be used for a rough estimation.
이 노드는 내부 버텍스는 보지 못하며, 거친 추정 용도로만 사용할 수 있다는 점을 참고하세요.
Next, let's kinematically constrain some muscle vertices that are close to bones.
다음으로, 뼈에 가까운 일부 근육 버텍스를 키네마틱하게 제약해 봅시다.
The node that we use is set flesh bone position target binding.
사용할 노드는 ‘Set Flesh Bone Position Target Binding’입니다.
For the skeletal binding mode here, let's select kinematic.
여기에서 Skeletal Binding Mode는 ‘Kinematic’을 선택합니다.
Because we're creating kinematic constraints between muscle and bones.
우리는 근육과 뼈 사이의 키네마틱 제약을 만들고 있기 때문입니다.
And vertex radius ratio controls the search radius between muscle and bones.
Vertex Radius Ratio는 근육과 뼈 사이의 검색 반경을 제어합니다.
So that the muscle vertices that's close to the bones are being constrained.
그렇게 해서 뼈에 가까운 근육 버텍스들이 제약을 받게 됩니다.
Here 0.001 means this is only 0.1% of the largest side of the bounding box of the collection.
여기서 0.001은 컬렉션 바운딩 박스의 가장 긴 변 길이의 0.1%라는 뜻입니다.
So think about the bounding box of this muscle geometry being the distance from the left hand to the right hand.
이 근육 지오메트리의 바운딩 박스를 왼손에서 오른손까지의 거리라고 생각해 보세요.
So that's 0.1 of that distance.
즉, 그 거리의 0.1%입니다.
It's being used as the search radius for creating that constraint.
이 값은 해당 제약을 만들 때의 검색 반경으로 사용됩니다.
Alternatively, there's also the position target mode.
대안으로 ‘Position Target’ 모드도 있습니다.
A position target, or sometimes I can call it a weak constraint,
‘Position Target’(때로는 ‘약한 제약(Weak Constraint)’이라고도 부름)은
is basically a spring connecting two sets of vertices.
본질적으로 두 버텍스 집합을 연결하는 스프링입니다.
For example, a vertex to vertex,
예를 들어 버텍스‑버텍스, 또는
or a vertex to a barycentric point in a triangle.
삼각형 내부의 바리센트릭 점과 버텍스를 연결할 수 있습니다.
The distance between the source position and the target position will be penalized during the solver evolution.
현재 위치와 목표 위치 사이의 거리는 솔버가 진행되는 동안 페널티로 처리됩니다.
The main difference between a weak constraint and the kinematic constraint
약한 제약과 키네마틱 제약의 주요 차이는
is that a weak constraint is allowed to be off from its target position.
약한 제약은 목표 위치에서 약간 벗어나는 것이 허용된다는 점입니다.
And the strength of the spring can be set through the stiffness parameter here, for example.
그리고 스프링의 강도(세기)는 여기 있는 Stiffness 파라미터 등으로 설정할 수 있습니다.
Now let's go ahead and set the skeletal mesh here.
이제 여기 Skeletal Mesh를 설정해 봅시다.
We'll assign the same bone skeletal mesh here.
뼈용 Skeletal Mesh를 동일하게 지정합니다.
In this example, let's set the vertex radius ratio to be 0.005.
이 예제에서는 Vertex Radius Ratio를 0.005로 설정하겠습니다.
And now we can move visualized kinematic faces here.
이제 ‘Visualize Kinematic Faces’를 여기로 가져와 보겠습니다.
So that you will see more kinematic faces.
그러면 더 많은 키네마틱 페이스가 보일 것입니다.
These are the vertices or faces from muscles.
이는 근육에서 온 버텍스 또는 페이스들입니다.
That's being kinematically constrained to bones.
이것들은 뼈에 키네마틱하게 제약되어 있습니다.
Next, we'll also need some muscle-muscle constraints so that the muscle doesn't flop around during the simulation.
다음으로, 시뮬레이션 중에 근육이 흐물거리지 않도록 몇 가지 약한(weak) 제약도 필요합니다.
Let's go ahead and create a set vertex triangle position target binding.
이제 ‘Set Vertex‑Triangle Position Target Binding’을 만들겠습니다.
This node creates point triangle springs between connected geometries.
이 노드는 연결된 지오메트리들 사이에 점‑삼각형 스프링을 만듭니다.
In this case, between muscles.
이 경우에는 근육들 사이입니다.
Let's go ahead and set the vertex ratio to be 0.004.
Vertex Radius Ratio를 0.004로 설정합시다.
And this stiffens to be 10.
그리고 Stiffness는 10으로 설정합니다.
The vertex radius ratio works the same way as the previous node.
Vertex Radius Ratio는 이전 노드와 동일한 방식으로 동작합니다.
Now we can visualize the weak constraints through visualize position target node.
이제 ‘Visualize Position Target’ 노드를 통해 약한 제약을 시각화할 수 있습니다.
You can go ahead and turn on the top right button here to render it.
우측 상단 버튼을 켜서 렌더링하도록 하세요.
Now you can see these are little line segments painted in red.
이제 빨간색으로 칠해진 작은 선분들이 보일 겁니다.
That represents the weak constraints.
이것이 약한 제약을 나타냅니다.
So these are between muscles and muscles.
즉, 근육과 근육 사이에 걸려 있습니다.
Now the next step here is optional.
다음 단계는 선택 사항입니다.
At this point, we can check the skin weights of the kinematic vertices.
이 시점에서 키네마틱 버텍스의 스킨 웨이트를 확인할 수 있습니다.
Let's go to vertices group.
‘Vertices’ 그룹으로 가봅시다.
And then near the end, we see bone weight index and bone weights.
하단 쪽에 ‘Bone Weight Index’와 ‘Bone Weights’가 보입니다.
These are the linear blend skinning weights that we'll use to skin the kinematic vertices.
이는 키네마틱 버텍스를 스키닝하는 데 사용할 선형 블렌드 스키닝 가중치입니다.
You can see most of them are rigid.
대부분이 Rigid(경직)인 것을 볼 수 있습니다.
Because you see a skin weight of one and then that's associated to only one transform.
가중치가 1인 뼈 하나에만 연관되어 있기 때문이죠.
If you have a better skinning on the skeletal mesh that you want to use,
더 나은 스키닝이 적용된 Skeletal Mesh가 있다면,
you'll be able to transfer the skin weights from the skeletal mesh to the tetrahedral mesh now.
지금 그 Skeletal Mesh에서 테트라 메쉬로 스킨 웨이트를 전송(transfer)할 수 있습니다.
So let's go ahead and create a transfer skin weight, vertex skin weights node.
‘Transfer Skin Weights’—‘Vertex Skin Weights’ 노드를 생성합시다.
And then from collection, let's give that the skeletal mesh collection.
‘From Collection’에는 Skeletal Mesh 컬렉션을 지정합니다.
We have this muscle skeletal mesh collection here.
여기 근육 Skeletal Mesh 컬렉션이 있습니다.
So let's connect that all the way here.
그래서 그것을 여기까지 연결해 줍니다.
Note that this almost works exactly the same way as the transfer here, transfer vertex attribute.
참고로, 이것은 여기의 ‘Transfer Vertex Attribute’와 거의 같은 방식으로 동작합니다.
So I'll skip the explanation here.
그래서 이 부분의 자세한 설명은 생략하겠습니다.
But note that this also only work if there's the same number of geometries between collection and from collection.
다만, 이것 역시 ‘From/To Collection’ 간 지오메트리 수가 같아야만 한다는 제약이 있습니다.
We'll fix that in 5.6.
이 문제는 5.6에서 수정할 예정입니다.
So now, if you go to vertices, you can see now the bone weights changed.
이제 ‘Vertices’로 가보면, 뼈 가중치가 바뀐 것을 볼 수 있습니다.
They're more like a blend instead of the rigid skinning before.
이전의 Rigid 스키닝 대신 블렌드에 더 가까워졌죠.
So again, this step is optional in case you want to use the skin weights on the sculptal mesh, which is the muscles.
다시 말하지만, 이 단계는 선택 사항이며 근육용 Skeletal Mesh의 스킨 웨이트를 사용하려는 경우에 유용합니다.
Lastly, let's create a flesh asset terminal.
마지막으로 ‘Flesh Asset Terminal’을 생성합시다.
We've seen this node.
이 노드는 전에 본 적이 있습니다.
We can now save the collection into the flesh asset here.
이제 컬렉션을 Flesh Asset에 저장할 수 있습니다.
Now we should be able to see our flesh asset in the simulation viewport.
이제 시뮬레이션 뷰포트에서 우리의 Flesh Asset을 볼 수 있을 겁니다.
As a recap, now we define the kinematic constraints between muscles and bones.
정리하면, 이제 근육과 뼈 사이의 키네마틱 제약을 정의했고,
We define weak constraints between muscles.
근육끼리의 약한 제약도 정의했습니다.
In the next video, we'll start simulating the muscles.
다음 영상에서는 근육 시뮬레이션을 시작하겠습니다.
But there has been some Marcelinoids also to look at his Brockley Mock.
하지만 일부 마르셀리노이드도 그의 브록클리 목을 보기 위해 있었다.
He's called the healer.
그는 힐러라고 불립니다.
There tuvo me confidence in good au Memory.
좋은 메모리에 대한 자신감이 있었습니다.
And this is the second one.
그리고 이것이 두 번째 것입니다.